

# **Gulbala Salamov**

## **Software Developer**

Office Location: Saint Petersburg, Russia Place of Residence: Ankara, Turkey Nationality: Turkish, Azerbaijan

## Personal Profile

I am a Software Developer with a Researcher experience from reputable universities. I have improved skills in problem identification and implementation of effective solutions. I have good interpersonal communication and social skills.

I'd like to invest in myself further with top skills modern engineers need to succeed. I have 3 years experience in agile software engineering practices from conception to completion and 1 year active professional programming experience. Recently my focus shifts into best practices applied in the industry and thus I am looking forward to developing new solutions integrating applications across enterprise or its units.

## **Education**

BS, Computer Education & Instructional Technologies 2010 – 2014 Middle East Technical University, Turkey

MSc, Computer Science 2014 – 2016 Swansea University, U.K.

# Professional Experience

Software Developer & Technical Writer – eSystems Nordic Feb. 2022 – till present (Full Time, Remote)

Researcher & Jr. Software Developer – University College London, U.K. Apr 2019 - June 2020 (Full Time)

Researcher & Developer Intern – State University of New York, U.S.A June 2017 - Sep 2017 (Full Time)

Jr. Software Development Specialist – SIP Azerbaijan Sep 2013 - Sep 2016 (Part Time, Project based)

ICT Teacher Intern – Middle East Technical University, Turkey Feb 2014 - June 2014 (Part Time)

ICT Teacher Intern – Private Ari Schools, Turkey
Feb 2014 - June 2014 (Part Time)

#### Contact

+90 536 710 2202

- <sup>1</sup> github.com/gulbalasalamov
- <sup>2</sup> <u>linkedin.com/in/gulbalasalamov</u>
- <sup>3</sup> g.salamov@gmail.com

# Languages

- TURKISH MOTHER
- AZERBAIJAN MOTHER
- ENGLISH BUSINESS
- RUSSIAN INTERMEDIATE
- GERMAN BEGINNER

#### 5 Words to Describe Me

- Problem solver
- Consistent
- Kind
- Positive
- Enthusiastic

## Industry Experience

- ICT Services
- Education
- Healthcare & Life Sciences
- Travel & Hospitality

## Major Projects

#### ECSAnVIs

Extreme Citizen Science Analysis and Visualisation (ECSAnVis) is a five-years, €2.5M project funded by the European Research Council (ERC), aiming at the development of geographical analysis and visualisation tools that can be used, successfully, by non-literate people and any other community in a culturally appropriate ways, that further fit their needs and social practices.

The work further builds on Sapelli, an open-source Android project that facilitates data collection through highly configurable icon-driven user interfaces. The transmission of complete records is handled autonomously to another phone using sms or a GeoKey web server.

https://www.geog.ucl.ac.uk/research/research-centres/excites/projects/extreme-citizen-science-analysis-and-visualisation-ecsanvis

## My role - Android Developer

Apr 2019 - June 2020

- Designed and implemented interactive prototypes for Sapelli Visualiser to display collected geographically meaningful.
- Maintained Sapelli Collector, fixed bugs, added new functionalities.
- Picked up existing code base, wrote better and maintainable code.
- Improved the documentation further using GitHub as a source management repository.
- Contributed to academic research, presentations and workshops

### Applications:

o Android, Java, SQL, Python, Adobe XD, Git

# Skillset (Level 1-5)

1 - Poor, 2 - Modest, 3 - Average, 4 - Good, 5 - Excellent

| A. PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES                     | LEVEL OF<br>COMPETENCE |
|--|------------------------|
| Android                                      | ••••                   |
| Java   | •••00                  |
| SQL  | •••00                  |
| Version CS (Git, Github)                     | ••••                   |
| Code Organization (OOP, FP, Design Patterns) | ••••                   |
| Testing Framework (Debugging, Junit5)        | ••000                  |

## What Motivates Me

- Solving real life problems by building software solutions
- Researching and creating contents both educational and scientific
- Learning and sharing my knowledge



Interpersonal Communication

**Social Skills** 

Team Player

Fast Learner

| B. SERVER SIDE TECHNOLOGIES                                | LEVEL OF COMPETENCE |
|--|---------------------|
| Java   | ••••                |
| Framework (Spring)   | ••000               |
| Spring Framework Core<br>(Configuration, MVC, DI)          | ••000               |
| Spring Security (JWT, Auth & Authentication)               | ••000               |
| Spring Boot Databases (Spring Data JPA, PostgreSQL, MySQL) | ••••                |

| C. FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES  | LEVEL OF COMPETENCE |
|----------------------------|---------------------|
| Language (CSS, HTML)       | ••••                |
| Framework (Angular)        | •0000               |
| Prototype (AdobeXD, Figma) | ••••                |

| D. LOW-CODE & NO-CODE TECH | LEVEL OF COMPETENCE |
|----------------------------|---------------------|
| OutSystems                 | ••000               |

| E. OTHER SKILLS  | LEVEL OF COMPETENCE |
|--|---------------------|
| Additional Tools (Jira, Slack, Teams)                                  | ••••                |
| Soft Skills (Communication, Patience,<br>Time Management, Open Minded) | ••••                |
| Useful Skills (R & D, Academic Writings)                               | ••••                |

# What am I most proud of

I've a passion to share my knowledge. So, to help novice programmers and students I published Android Mobile Programming book written in Java which was recommended supplementary text book in Turkish universities in 2017.

https://www.kitapyurdu.com/kitap/android-sanati/434078.html

I have also contributed to a number of scientific research and co-authored in academic publications.



IELTS Score: 6.5

2018